JUAN UREÑA

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINNER

+34 626486347 JUALUR01@GMAIL.COM



in HTTPS://WWW.LINKEDIN.COM/IN/JUANALBERTOURE%C3%B1ARODR%C3%ADGUEZ/



HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/JAUR001

I am a software engineer specialized in Java. I have been programming in this language for 4 years during the degree. I want to develop my professional career as a Java developer because in this language I feel the most comfortable to work with, besides that is the one that I can program more complex applications. I have worked during 8 months in The Singular Factory as a Software Engineer, developing different software products. I am motivated to develop and improve my skills in this sector and grow professionally.

CONTENTS

Juan	ា Ureña	1
	Skills	2
	Work Experience	3
	Education	4
	Main Projects	5
	Small Projects	7
	Achievements and certifications	۵

SKILLS

LANGUAGES

- Java 4 years hands-on experience: during the degree where I mainly used this language to develop different projects: Webapps, Data mining, Swing or JavaFX application, REST and SOAP web services... etc.
- Frontend: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript.
- Other languages: Python, C, C++, C#, SQL.

FRAMEWORKS

- Java Frameworks: Spring (MVC, AOP, Security, REST, Boot), Hibernate.
- JavaScript Frameworks: Express.js, Node.js, Vue.js, AngularJS.

TOOLS AND OTHER SKILLS

- Java IDEs: IntelliJ, Eclipse, NetBeans.
- Other IDEs: WebStorm, Visual Studio.
- Java libraries and technologies: JSP, Java websockets, Java Servlets, Jsoup.
- JavaScript libraries: Ajax, Bootstrap.
- Text format: XML, JSON, CSV
- Version Control: Git, GitHub.
- **Dependency control:** Maven
- SQL relational databases: MySQL, SQLite.
- NoSQL relational databases: MongoDB.
- Servers: Apache Tomcat, Apache TomEE, Glassfish
- Testing: Unit and Integration Test, Junit, TDD.
- Principles: Object-Oriented Programming, MVC, SOLID, Design Patterns, Clean Code, Agile Development, SCRUM, Software Architecture.
- Other: Team worker, fast learning, adaptability, highly motivated, Advanced IT English level, communicative skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

JUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

THE SINGULAR FACTORY | JANUARY 2020 - MAY 2020

I contributed to the development inside a team of a module of a company's application for maintenance, inventory and tasks (Qiip). The team was composed by 3 Junior developers (included me), one Senior developer and the leader. This module was developed to adapt the application for concrete client, a town hall that wanted to administrate the cemetery with this software where I mainly developed the Frontend part (I also helped in certain moments in the Backend). We needed to add new features and options and delete others that were not necessary. The development was guided the CRUD principle in which all equipment, tasks, locations and inventory can be created, retrieved, updated and deleted. The project was developed using the following technologies:

- Frontend: Vue.js (Javascript) and company's developed library for styles (similar to Bootstrap).
- Back-end: Symfony (php) and API Platform for database management.
- Others: PHPStorm IDE for Backend and WebStorm IDE for Frontend, Postman to check HTTP requests,
 JSON to manage different languages via one JSON file for each language and Git + GitBurns (developed
 by the company) for version control.

INTERSHIP - JUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

THE SINGULAR FACTORY | OCTOBER 2019 – JANUARY 2020

I developed an application to control the time and different measures of it, as Internet Time or UTC. I programmed the application to be available in Android with AngularJS and in IOS (iPhone and Apple Watch) with XCode IDE and Swift language.

Besides, I researched a solution to integrate ArcGIS (an external application of the company for mapping), with an application of the company explained before (Qiip). They wanted to have an option for the clients that have also ArcGIS pro to show in a map where are located the elements selected in the application. I offered different possible solutions that I found:

- Using the API offered by ArcGIS to use the different functionalities.
- Redirect to ArcGIS web to show there the map of the location.
- Open the Desktop app for ArcGIS automatically to show there instead.
- Create a websocket using the port offered by the ArcGIS to obtain information about locations and maps.

However, they did not continue with that idea of integration because none of the options where selected. The reasons are the next:

- The first option was the best to show the maps, but the clients could not take advantages of the account they pay for ArcGIS pro because they use an API instead.
- The second did not offer an option to send a location and show in a map after login. The client should login and manually go to the location. Besides there were no options to connect the elements offered by ArcGIS with the elements of Qiip.
- The third could work for the Desktop Qiip app, but not for the Web application.
- The fourth was the option that I proved that worked, but they did not continue because it take a lot of time to develop and would make to change the code already made. In conclusion, it was not profitable because there were interested a few clients that had also the ArcGIS pro, so they opted to cancel the idea.

Finally, after this I joined the team to develop the module explained before during the rest of the practice contract and continuing during the temporal contract as a Junior developer.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSIDAD DE LAS PALMAS DE GRAN CANARIA

COMPUTER SCIENCE WITH SOFTWARE ENGINEER SPECIALIZATION
SEPTEMBER 2020 – MAY 2020

My main degree where I learned everything about the IT's sector. During the four years of studies, I learned everything mainly with the Java language, so I know ample number of different technologies, frameworks and libraries of it and I have a lot experience and comfort programming in this language. During this degree I got these skills:

- Ability to robustly, securely and efficiently analyze, design, build and maintain applications
- Ability to design, develop, select and evaluate computer applications and systems, ensuring their reliability, security and quality
- Design, develop, implement, verify and document software solutions based on adequate knowledge of current theories, models and techniques.

I also made the final project, "Finbook", programmed mainly in Java where I got a 9.1/10 and mentioned for honors, that was explained before.

AKADEMIA GÓRNICZO-HUTNICZA IM. STANISŁAWA STASZICA W KRAKOWIF

COMPUTER SCIENCE WITH SOFTWARE ENGINEER SPECIALIZATION

JANUARY 2020 – MAY 2020

I went one-year Erasmus to Krakow to study in the AGH continuing mainly with the specialization of Software Engineer. During this year I learned:

- Agile methodology, SCRUM and Project management.
- User interface designing
- Python, C++
- Web development (HTML5, CSS, JavaScript), frameworks (Express.js, Node.js) and MongoDB (NoSQL).
- Data analysis
- Computer Network

MAIN PROJECTS

FINBOOK - INVOICE SIMULATOR - WEBAPP | OCTOBER 2019 - JULY 2020

This project was the my final project and part of a Big data project developed by 4 Junior Java developers and a Senior developer that guided us. It is a Web application that simulate a virtual economic environment formed by companies that buy and sell products and service. These companies act in function of certain parameters and strategies to get the highest benefits and maintaining the rules and laws in the reality (e.g. Minimum salaries for the employers). All these Economy of Market works based of demands.

During the execution the simulator will generate a high volume of invoices or bills that can be analyzed by other programs or processed by Big data applications, like in the case of this project. The rest of the modules of the main project use these invoices to generate reports about taxes automatically or to calculate the financial state of the companies. the bills will be saved in the xmlFiles folder located in "src/main/java/web/" folder.

The Web application allows the user to change the settings to get a simulation adapted to their needs.

Besides, it allows to check what is happening inside the simulation by the Event Box that shows all the events that happened during the execution and decide which Companies, Clients or Worker to track to show the

events only of these ones. The user can download all the bills generated he wants from the Web client to read them or to process with other programs.

This project was focused on the Backend (more than 250 classes) side to get the most reliability and realistic Virtual Economic Simulation and to be scalable using the base Architecture developed.

Install/Execute

- The project has no Framework dependency, so it is necessary to have the server downloaded apart.
- The project uses the Tomcat Server, so the server downloaded must be Tomcat.
- Then, it is only need to clone and execute the project with the Tomcat server.

Built with

Backend

- Java Language
- Tomcat Server Server for Backend
- SQLite Browse SQL Relational DB Management System Application
- Maven Dependency Management

Frontend

- JSP, JavaScript and CSS Languages for Web designing
- Jquery Library to control the Web Requests and Data-Flow

For more information: https://github.com/jaur001/SimulatorServer

FINBOOK - INVOICE SIMULATOR - DESKTOP APP | OCTOBER 2019 - FEBRUARY 2020

This project is the desktop version of Simulator explained before. It is focused on the main objective, generate a high volume of invoices. There is no user interface and the important data is displayed in the console.

For more information: https://github.com/jaur001/Simulator

KEY FINDER APP | OCTOBER 2019 - JANUARY 2020

This application is an IFTTT Desktop Application which checks daily the games that the users are interested, and if the price is lower than price selected by the use, then the user is notified by mail with the games and prices that has been lowered. The app was developed in Java and has these features:

- It allows to have different accounts with different games selected.
- The Graphic User Interface was developed using JavaFX.
- The prices are checked via Internet in https://www.allkeyshop.com/blog/ using JSoup library.
- The mails are sent using the Javax's Mail library and SMTP protocol
- The project was tested using TDD technique with Unit and Integration testing.

INSTALL/EXECUTE

Clone and execute the Main.class located in "src/main/java/main" package.

BUILD WITH

- JavaFX To develop the Graphic User Interface
- Maven Dependency Management

For more information: https://github.com/jaur001/KeyFinderApp

SMALL PROJECTS

TDD APPS

I have done different TDD projects to train this programming's technique during the last year of my bachelor's degree. All the projects are refactored by using functional programming. Examples are:

- https://github.com/jaur001/StringCalculatorTDD
- https://github.com/jaur001/NumberBreakdown
- https://github.com/jaur001/RomanNumerals

IMAGE VIEWER - DECEMBER 2019

This application allows to see images and change to previous or next one (It works similar as Windows's Photos application). It was developed in Java. The photo resizes when you resizes the windows and adapts to the measures of it.

INSTALL/EXECUTE

Clone and execute

BUILD WITH

• Java - Language

For more information: https://github.com/jaur001/ImageViewer

MONEY CALCULATOR - OCTOBER 2019

This application calculates the exchange rate from one currency to other one. The user writes an amount, the currency of the money and the currency to change as an input and receives the total amount of that output. The list of exchanges rates is obtained by a REST web service https://www.currencyconverterapi.com/.

INSTALL/EXECUTE

- Get your own key for the Currency API or use the one in the application
- Clone and execute

BUILD WITH

- Java Language
- REST Web Service

For more information: https://github.com/jaur001/MoneyCalculator

UNIVERSITY MOODLE PLATFORM - MAY 2019

This project is Web application to support teachers and students with the marks of the different subjects. The users with the teacher role put marks in the subject they teach and the ones with Student role check the marks of every subject. All the data is saved in MongoDB database (NoSQL).

INSTALL/EXECUTE

It is necessary Node.js to execute it. Clone the project and execute the app.js file with Node.js.

BUILT WITH

BACKEND

- JavaScript Language
- Node.js Environment to program Backend with JavaScript
- Express.js Framework to program in Node.js
- MongoDB NoSQL Database Management System

FRONTEND

- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS
- PUG files
- EJS files

For more information: https://github.com/jaur001/University-Moodle-Platform

ACHIEVEMENTS AND CERTIFICATIONS

- MENTIONED FOR HONORS IN MY BACHELOR'S DEGREE FINAL PROJECT: "FINBOOK".
- SPRING & HIBERNATE FOR BEGINNERS COURSE CHAD DARBY UDEMY COURSE - 43 HOURS



- MASTER MICROSERVICES WITH SPRING BOOT AND SPRING CLOUD –
 IN28MINUTES UDEMY COURSE 12 HOURS
- MENTION OF JOSE JUAN HERNANDEZ CABRERA SENIOR DEVELOPER AND LEADER IN DIFFERENT COMPANIES, TEACHER DURING MY DEGREE AND TUTOR DURING MY FINAL PROJECT - MORE THAN 30 YEARS OF EXPERIENCE

Prof. José Juan Hernández Cabrera Universidad de Las Palmas de Gran Canaria Campus Universitario de Tafira. 35017. Las Palmas Spain



To whom it may concern

I have known Juan Ureña since September 2019 when he became one my student for a whole term in Software Engineering in the third year of the degree. He is a very responsible student and is committed with his goals. In addition, I would highlight his fast learning ability. He showed not only a high capacity to understand completely the content of the course but also to go beyond that content and fully understand the risks, payloads, advantages and many others of the different architectures, design patterns and good programming practices.

Apart from the academic perspective, I want to stress the learning interest that Juan owns. He is developing interesting side projects related with Data Science. Juan has showed high academic standards and intellectual abilities to his substantive area of interest. He also presents a sociable attitude and great communication skills.

In conclusion, I highly recommend Juan, as I firmly believe he is well-prepared to undertake any challenge in Software Engineer.

Please, feel free to contact directly if you need any additional information.

Sincerely,

HERNANDEZ
CABRERA JOSE
JUAN - 43751594M
Fecha: 2020.08.28 09:36:21
+01'00'

E. josejuan.hernandez@ulpgc.es M. +34.616.666.961